insydium.ltd 2019-11-30

# INSYDIUM LTD | INSYDIUM LTD Privacy Policy

**The Website**

This website and its owners take your privacy seriously. This website complies to all UK national laws and requirements for user privacy.

**Who is collecting your data?**

When you place an order, or make an enquiry on our website, you are sending your personal data to INSYDIUM LTD - Registered in England Company registration no. 08615238 – VAT Number GB 179 7156 59.

**What data is being collected?**

If you register on our website as a consumer, we ask you to submit your full name, email address and postal address. If you register as a business you can also, optionally, gives us your company name and VAT number. Our website also gives us your IP address and country.

**What is the legal basis for processing the data?**

  1. When you order one of our software products, you will need a valid license to use it. We need to collect and store the data you give us so that we can give you a license and record that fact that you have one.
  2. We also need to keep a record of your data so that we can contact you with any maintenance updates you are entitled to.
  3. Finally, we need to store your data if you have consented to allow us to send you newsletters or marketing emails.

**Will the data be shared with any third parties?**

If you give us your consent, we will save your data on MAILCHIMP to send you the emails you have asked for and it will be passed to PAYPAL to process your payment. We don’t share your data with any other third parties.

**How will the information be used?**

Your data will be stored on our internal database system, our software licensing server, our accounting software and in your INSYDIUM website shop account. It will be used to purely to contact you about your license and maintenance and not for any other purpose.

**How long will the data be stored for?**

Your data will be kept on our systems for as long as you are an active customer of INSYDIUM LTD.

**What is your right of access?**

You can ask us to send you a copy of any personal data of yours that we have. If you no longer want us to keep that data, you can ask us to remove it from our systems at any time by contacting [privacy@insydium.com](mailto:sales@insydium.com). However, remember that if you ask us to delete your data we will no longer be able to provide you with an active license for our software.

**Use of Cookies**

For this website to work properly it uses cookies. Cookies are small files saved to the user’s computer hard drive that track, save and store information about the user’s interactions and usage of the website.

When first visiting the website, users are advised that cookies are being used and are given the opportunity to accept that.

If they wish to deny the use and saving of cookies from this website on to their computers hard drive they should take necessary steps within their web browsers security settings to block all cookies from this website and its external serving vendors.

This website uses tracking software to monitor its visitors to better understand how they use it. This software is provided by Google Analytics which uses cookies to track visitor usage. The software will save a cookie to your computers hard drive in order to track and monitor your engagement and usage of the website, but will not store, save or collect personal information. You can read Google’s privacy policy here for further information http://www.google.com/privacy.html. You can optionally choose to opt-out of allowing Google Analytics using Google’s opt-out feature here.

Other cookies may be stored to your computers’ hard drive by external vendors when this website uses referral programs, sponsored links or adverts. Such cookies are used for conversion and referral tracking and typically expire after 30 days, though some may take longer. No personal information is stored, saved or collected.

**External Links**

Although this website only looks to include quality, safe and relevant external links, users are advised adopt a policy of caution before clicking any external web links mentioned throughout this website. (External links are clickable text / banner / image links to other websites, similar to: www.google.com and Google this.)

The owners of this website cannot guarantee or verify the contents of any externally linked website despite their best efforts. Users should therefore note they click on external links at their own risk and this website and its owners cannot be held liable for any damages or implications caused by visiting any external links mentioned.

**Social Media Platforms**

Communication, engagement and actions taken through external social media platforms that this website and its owners participate on are custom to the terms and conditions as well as the privacy policies held with each social media platform respectively.

Users are advised to use social media platforms wisely and communicate / engage upon them with due care and caution in regard to their own privacy and personal details. This website nor its owners will ever ask for personal or sensitive information through social media platforms and encourage users wishing to discuss sensitive details to contact them through primary communication channels such as by telephone or email.

This website may use social sharing buttons which help share web content directly from web pages to the social media platform in question. Users are advised before using such social sharing buttons that they do so at their own discretion and note that the social media platform may track and save your request to share a web page respectively through your social media platform account.

**Shortened Links in Social Media**

This website and its owners through their social media platform accounts may share web links to relevant web pages. By default, some social media platforms shorten lengthy URLs.

Users are advised to take caution and good judgement before clicking any shortened URLs published on social media platforms by this website and its owners. Despite the best efforts to ensure only genuine URLs are published many social media platforms are prone to spam and hacking and therefore this website and its owners cannot be held liable for any damages or implications caused by visiting any shortened links.

**Resources & Further Information**

v.2.0 May 2018 by: INSYDIUM LTD Registered in England Company registration no. 08615238 – VAT Number GB 179 7156 59
